Igor Santos

Software Engineer | Computer Science | AWS Certified | Back-End Developer

Santo André, SP. Brazil +55 11 99757-2385 igorneysantos@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ igor-santos-ufabc

Resume

Computer Science student working as a Software Developer. I have experience with distributed systems, microservices, Ibm MQ, Pub/Sub Kafka, container platforms using kubernetes like openshift. Still, I have experience with AWS services and solutions. Iac like terraform, Devops and Ci/Cd using github and github actions. I really like learning new things and working with different areas. I'm always willing to teach and face new challenges.

Experience

Itaú Unibanco, Brazil — Junior Software Developer

August 2021 - Current

Migrated microservices from PaaS on Openshift to AWS Cloud in an Event-driven architecture. Collaborated with development team members to create and integrate high availability solutions for mission-critical banking applications.

Itaú Unibanco, Brazil — Software Developer Intern

March 2020 - August 2021

Generated efficient, modular and maintainable back-end code. Designed and implemented backend models and API endpoints for complex workflows.

Kuka Systems, Brazil — Software Developer Intern

May 2019 - January 2020

Maintenance and support of a monolithic system. Backup and updates of the financial and human resources system to generate data for the company's management and direction.

Education

Universidade Federal do ABC, Brazil — Bachelor

June 2018 - Dec 2024

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Skills

Terraform

Microservices

Apache Kafka

RedHat Openshift

REST APIs

Java Spring Boot

Github

Certifications

Amazon Web Services Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS Academy Cloud

Developing

AWS Academy Cloud

Foundations

SQL (Basic) Certified

Java (Basic) Certified

Python (Basic) Certified

Languages

Portuguese: First Language

English: Intermediate

Spanish: Intermediate